Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/williamkidd (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Due Diligence Investment Banking Equities

Certifications

Series 7, 16, 63, 86 & 87

Honors-Awards

2005

2003

2002

1999

2000

William Kidd

Manager Corporate Strategy at Verizon

Greater Houston

Summary

Truth dealer, skilled leader, team builder and trusted advisor. His financial skill set is in corporate and financial strategy, value creation, investment analysis, valuation, and industry/company/financial modeling.

Prior to joining Verizon, he was a Director at Informa Tech / Omdia, a TMT market research, intelligence and consulting services company, where he was responsible for the financial services business and leading commercial due diligence consulting engagements, supporting M&A and investment activity. He consulted private equity, hedge funds, commercial and investment banks, and industry clients.

He has also held held senior leadership equity research roles at leading investment banks: Lehman Brothers, HSBC Securities, C.E. Unterberg, Towbin, and Wedbush Morgan Securities. Personally ranked as a top Wall Street industry analyst by fund managers and analysts through organizations like Institutional Investor, Greenwich Associates, Forbes and Buyside magazine, while covering satellites, media and technology.

Experience

Verizon

Manager Corporate Strategy (Global Enterprise)
March 2020 - Present (3 years 2 months)

Remote (position in NJ HQ)

Research, develop, recommend and present board-level strategies and presentations for new and existing B2B verticals and products as well as annual and 5Y planning cycles. At present, driving and supporting global enterprise strategy with prior B2B strategy team experience in public sector, wholesale and competitive intelligence.

Focused on developing a new strategy and go-to-market plan for one of the company's most important growth projects/products—PaaS/laaS and mobile edge compute (MEC) including 5G private networks. In addition to supporting a broad array of wired and wireless products, worked on initiatives such as metaverse strategy, fixed wireless access, video games, dark fiber, and secure enclave (similar to an esim) and WFH investment opportunities such as remote learning.

Other related experience includes authoring quarterly competitive intelligence reports and supporting sales governance through product guardrails.

Omdia

Director Research & Analysis (TMT), Financial Services & Consulting April 2010 - March 2020 (10 years)

Los Angeles, CA

Omdia (parent Informa Tech) is a leading market intelligence and events company. Informa is listed on the London Stock Exchange and a member of the FTSE 100, with 11,000+ employees in 30+ countries and 500 TMT analysts. Joined Omdia through its 2019 acquisition of IHS Markit Technology. My role initially was at iSuppli, a private VC funded (incl Goldman Sachs) research firm that evolved into the preeminent semiconductor and electronics advisory firm and was the genesis of the IHS TMT business line.

Led the TMT financial services business, encompassing both consulting and subscription products, which grew revenue by 3x during my tenure. Most financial services consulting projects are commercial due diligence in nature, supporting M&A and investment activity. Clientele include private equity, institutional investors, hedge funds, venture capital and commercial and investment banks.

Commercial due diligence project track record included Ambarella, Atheros, Broadcom, Broadcom + Qualcomm + NXP, Freescale, Globalfoundries, Infineon, Marvell, MediaTek, Renesas, Skyworks, and Ultrahaptics. Also supported industry client driven competitive intelligence projects, assessing aspects such as M&A strategy.

Responsible for TechView, a subscription research service tailored to institutional investors. TechView's clientele included most major investment banks and many top 100 global asset managers. Published a TMT weekly report for institutional investors to drive customer engagement.

Wedbush Securities Vice President (Media), Equity Research 2007 - 2008 (1 year) Los Angeles, CA

Senior equity analyst for a major West Coast broker-dealer and investment bank with almost 1,000 employees. Established the firm's media research presence, covering pay television, film studios and cinema exhibitors. Recommended investment strategies based on insights, modeling and valuation, advising institutional investors and C-level management. Functioned as a sector expert and supervisory analyst, approving and editing research reports of other senior analysts.

Vintage Research
Partner and Managing Director (Media), Equity Research
2003 - 2006 (3 years)
New York, NY

Co-founded Vintage Research initially as an independent equity research/ consulting firm specializing in media and telecom equity research. Proposed and secured marketing and co-branding relationship with Janney Montgomery, an investment banking and financial services firm with over 1,000 employees, in which Vintage provided research and investment banking services. Vintage was consistently profitable.

Lehman Brothers
Vice President (Satellites & Pay TV), Equity Research
2001 - 2003 (2 years)
New York, NY

Global head of satellite and space equity research for the largest technology investment bank in the United States. Lehman ranked #1 in satellite sector investment banking transactions. Personally ranked #1 in quality as a satellites sector equity analyst by both Institutional Investor and Greenwich Associates in their rankings of Wall Street's best analysts; my highest client penetration rankings were #3 in the 2003 Greenwich poll, followed by #6 in 2002's Institutional Investor poll.

Performed the due diligence, valuation and approval for Lehman Brothers in conjunction with Lehman Brothers Merchant Banking's EUR550mn private equity investment in Eutelsat. The stake was monetized with a substantive profit in December 2004.

- Won lead-manager roles for the anticipated billion-dollar IPOs of both Intelsat and Eutelsat
- Won M&A advisory role for Intelsat's \$3 billion acquisition of PanAmSat
- Won lead-manager role for Dish Network's \$5 billion M&A bridge as part of its bid for DIRECTV
- Advised Liberty Media on its potential purchase of DIRECTV
- Advised on the restructuring and secondary offerings of Sirius Satellite Radio

C.E. Unterberg, Towbin

Partner and Managing Director (Satellites & Aerospace), Equity Research

1998 - 2001 (3 years)

New York, NY

C.E. Unterberg, Towbin (now part of Canaccord) was a leading technology investment banking firm with over 200 employees that also had private equity and venture capital funds. Personally built and oversaw the firm's most profitable equity research and investment banking franchise, in the satellite and space sector, while working in partnership with A. Robert Towbin. Regularly screened, pitched and advised investment banking clients on IPOs, secondary offerings and M&A.

Because of the strength of my C-level relationships, client engagement and research franchise, we participated in ~50% of public equity and debt offerings from my coverage group, an impressive feat from a mid-sized firm. Investment banking clients included Dish Network, L3 Communications, Loral Space, Pegasus, Sirius, ViaSat and XM Satellite. Also evaluated investment in early-stage technology companies on behalf of the partnership.

Education

Loyola Marymount University MBA, Finance · (1992 - 1993)